<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[A Large Tin Box]]></title>
  <link href="http://robertsawko.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://robertsawko.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-05-01T09:52:32+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://robertsawko.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Robert Sawko]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[It Is Alive!]]></title>
    <link href="http://robertsawko.github.io/blog/2015/04/30/it-is-alive/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-30T20:41:25+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://robertsawko.github.io/blog/2015/04/30/it-is-alive</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is my first post using <a href="http://octopress.org/">octopress</a> i.e. a git based
blogging engine. At the moment I am just testing various functionalities. Is
markdown <strong>bold</strong> working? Do we have MathJax? Let’s try the Boltzmann equation</p>

<script type="math/tex; mode=display">\begin{equation}
\frac{\partial f}{\partial t} 
+ \frac{\mathbf{p}}{m} \cdot \nabla f
+ \mathbf{F} \cdot \frac{\partial f}{\partial \mathbf{p}}
=
{\left(\frac{\partial f}{\partial t} \right)}_{\mathrm{collision}}
\end{equation}</script>

<p>And to test inline maths we will use $x^{2}+y^{2}=z^{2}$ where $x$, $y$ are
catheti and $z$ is a hypotenuse of a right triangle. Here I have a ridiculous
problem of being forced to use curly brackets around each exponent.</p>

<p>At this stage I had to fight a small battle which involved messing around with
some files.  At the moment I am using the advice given on this
<a href="http://www.idryman.org/blog/2012/03/10/writing-math-equations-on-octopress/">post</a>
with <em>javascript</em> code
<code>source/_includes/custom/head.html</code>
which looks like a cleaner solution. But that wasn’t enough. After uploading
the files on Github Pages they wouldn’t display even though I could see them in
the preview mode. The reason was the HTTP secure access to MathJax. It’s
important that CDN address contains <code>https</code> rather than <code>http</code>. There’s a 
<a href="http://docs.mathjax.org/en/latest/start.html#secure-cdn-access">passage</a> in
MathJax documentation about it.</p>

<p>MathJax test passed. The plan is to run this as a little experiment in curiosity, amusement and
memory of all these little intellectual pursuits which somehow get lost in the
daily routine of existence. I would like to focus here on the work I do related
to fluid dynamics and coding but other content may appear too. The first few
steps though I need make is to investigate:</p>

<ul>
  <li>adding sub-pages,</li>
  <li>add contact info,</li>
  <li>test iPython integration,</li>
  <li>check comment functionalities (in the unlikely case someone wants to
comment!),</li>
  <li>theme customization.</li>
</ul>

<p>Interestingly at this stage the lists were <strong>not</strong> indented properly. Again, I
found the
<a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/24794024/markdown-list-does-not-indent-using-octopress">instructions</a>
which fixed it though. During the whole process I was struck by the fact that I
am overwhelmed by the technological nomenclature. There’s lots of concepts here
I completely don’t understand or just heard about for the very first time.
Hopefully this will become less of an impediment as time goes on.</p>

<p>The first actual post to appear is going to be on the introduction to Kraichnan
theory of turbulence which I am reading about at the moment. Will try to
reproduce some of the results and test iPython integration. Future posts may
cover some adventures in population balance modelling, partial differential
with stochastic inputs and fluid dynamics problems.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
